Finding Aid for Scandinavian Fraternity of America, North Star Lodge No. 27 (Escanaba, Mich.) records, 1887-1970
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Scandinavian Fraternity of America, North Star Lodge No. 27 (Escanaba, Mich.) records 1887-1970
Scandinavian Fraternity of America. North Star Lodge No. 27 (Escanaba, Mich.).
3 linear feet
85361 Bd 2
Minutes, cashbooks, and membership dues records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was the gift of the organization and came to the library through Dalip Rehnquist (donor no. 6198 ).
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
No further additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
According to some sources, the Scandinavian Fraternity of America was founded in 1894 as the Scandinavian Brotherhood of America. The records of the North Star Lodge in Escanaba pre-date the official founding of the organization by several years. In 1915, after consolidation with other organizations, the fraternity changed its name to the Scandinavian Fraternity of America. The Scandinavian Fraternity was principally a beneficial group dedicated to aiding members threatened by sickness, unemployment, or death. The organization was open to both women and men, and their non-Scandinavian spouses as well. The Fraternity attracted new immigrant members largely through an influx in Scandinavian immigration to the United States during the early 1920s.
The records of the organization include minutes of meetings, cashbooks, and records of dues paid by the membership. Most of the records are in Swedish.
Subjects:
Michigan--Emigration and immigration.; Escanaba (Mich.).; Scandinavian Americans--Michigan.; Swedish Americans--Michigan.; Scandinavia--Emigration and immigration.; Immigrants--Michigan.; Immigrants--Michigan--Societies, etc.
- Minutes
  - 1887-1891 (Box 1)
  - 1891-1896 (Box 1)
  - 1896-1900 (Box 1)
  - 1900-1905 (Box 1)
  - 1911-1916 (Box 1)
  - 1917-1929 (Box 1)
  - 1958-1967 (Box 1)
- Cashbook
  - 1887-1895 (Box 2)
  - 1895-1901 (Box 2)
  - 1902-1907 (Box 2)
  - 1907-1911 (Box 2)
  - 1932-1948 (Box 2)
  - 1949-1967 (Box 2)
- Other financial
  - Miscellaneous financial materials, 1965-1970 (Box 2)
- Membership records
  - Membership dues records, 6 volumes (Box 3)